



sharmaabhinav123@gmail.com



+91-9600088681



Hyderabad, India



linkedin.com/in/abhinav-sharma-2201



twitter.com/absharma\_2201

#### **SKILLS**

Programming: C, C++, Python

Kubernetes

Cloud-Native

**Envoy Proxy** 

Service Mesh

Microservices

**Distributed Systems** 

Multi-Cloud

## Abhinav Sharma

Dedicated, passionate software engineer with 7 years of progressive working experience in Distributed Systems and Cloud-Native technologies. Have interest in designing and crafting efficient modern software-defined network solutions, and learning new technologies and tools. I truly believe that there's always something new to learn, especially in IT-related fields.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer III, F5 Networks** F5 Distributed Cloud

07/2021 - Present Bengaluru, India

- As part of the Volterra Cloud team, contribute to the designing and implementation of solutions for F5 Distributed Cloud Services infrastructure.
- Involved in development of WAF and other network security features in Volterra Envoy Proxy.
- Supported in successful run of Envoy Proxy JavaScript functions on V8 engine workers.
- Added TCP/UDP proxy filters to handle EDNS (0) extensions to help improve DNS scalability.
- Developed multi-tenant tracing filter for improved service mesh monitoring and observability.

# **Software Engineer III, F5 Networks** Traffic Classification

12/2018 - 06/2021 Hyderabad, India

- Worked in Traffic Classification (DPI) module to analyse, classify and configure service policies on network traffic.
- Worked in Encrypted Video Classification module for detection of encrypted OTT traffic.
- Developed DFA signatures for VPN and other encrypted applications.
- Collaborated with fellow engineers to develop a transparent proxy module to decapsulate and analyse GTP-U 5G traffic.

### **Software Engineer II, Akamai Technologies** Media Analytics

11/2017 - 12/2018 Bengaluru, India

- □ Improved plugin data processing time by 30% for better real-time visibility into online streaming.
- Python script for check listing of health of Akamai Edge server components.

# **Software Engineer I, Akamai Technologies** Enterprise Security

06/2015 - 11/2017 Bengaluru, India

- Developed Walled Garden feature to force upgrade non-compliant devices.
- Designed and developed Web UI to report statistics for Distributed Systems Network Metadata Visualisation.
- Designed and developed Akamai in-house WCCPv2.0.
- □ Implemented State Machine to classify traffic flow as HTTP/2.

# **Software Engineer Intern, Akamai Technologies** Enterprise Security

01/2015 - 05/2015 Chennai, India

- Supported in development of protocol detection for a network traffic flow.
- Designed and delivered code for a Finite State Machine algorithm to detect the FTP flows.

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.Tech, Computer Science and Engineering**Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore(India)

06/2011 - 05/2015 8.9 CGPA

HSC (CBSE), Science & Maths DAV Public School, Jaipur(India)

05/2009 - 05/2010 74%